Emmet Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Emmet family papers
1792-1989 (bulk 1851-1989)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Emmet family
9.5 linear feet
The Emmet family papers measure 9.5 linear feet and date from 1792-1989 (bulk 1851-1989). The collection contains biographical material, diaries, correspondence, notes, writings, business records, a scrapbook, artwork, subject files, printed material, photographs, audio-visual material, and artifacts which present a good overview of the careers of portraitists, sisters Rosina Emmet Sherwood, Lydia Field Emmet, and Jane Erin Emmet De Glehn, and their cousin Ellen Gertrude "Bay" Emmet.
Biographical Note
The Emmet family, descended from patriot Thomas Addis Emmet, brother of Irish martyr Robert Emmet, counts many physicians, lawyers, and writers (including cousin Henry James) among its ranks. Although evidence of artistic talent existed in several previous generations, it flourished during the later 19th through the mid-20th centuries in the professional portraiture of sisters Rosina Emmet Sherwood, Lydia Field Emmet, Jane Erin Emmet De Glehn, and their cousin Ellen "Bay" Emmet Rand.
The eldest daughter of Julia Colt Pierson Emmet (1829-1908), herself a talented illustrator who had studied under Daniel Huntington, Rosina "Posie" Emmet (1854-1948) studied under William Merritt Chase at his Tenth Street Studio in New York and under Robert-Fleury at the Academie Julian in Paris. Before her marriage to Arthur Murray Sherwood in 1887, Rosina established a studio in New York and continued to submit illustrations to various publications. During her marriage, she slowed her creative activities, until financial reverses dictated her return to her career around the turn of the 20th century. Her daughter Rosamond Sherwood (1899-1990) was also a portrait painter. Her son, Robert Emmet Sherwood (1896-1955) became a four-time Pulitzer Prize-winning playwright.
Lydia Field Emmet (1866-1952) studied under Collin, Bouguereau, MacMonnies, and Robert-Fleury at the Academie Julian. Upon her return to New York, Lydia continued her studies under Chase, Kenyon Cox, H. Siddons Mowbray, and Robert Reid at the Art Students League, as well as at Chase's Shinnecock Summer School of Art. She established her portrait studio in New York City and began spending summers at Stockbridge, Massachusetts, where she built her home "Strawberry Hill" in 1905. Best known for her portraits of children, Lydia's subjects were members of the socially prominent families of New York, Boston, and Philadelphia.
The youngest sister, Jane Erin Emmet (1873-1961), also studied with Chase in New York, and in Paris. In 1904, she married British landscape painter Wilfrid Von Glehn, who had visited the United States with his friend John Singer Sargent. (The Von Glehns' surname was changed to De Glehn, in 1919.) Settling in London, Jane continued her painting, befriended many artists and composers, and accompanied her husband and Sargent on several art-related journeys through Europe.
The Emmet sisters' cousin, Ellen Gertrude "Bay" Emmet (1875-1941), studied in New York at the Art Students League and under Frederick MacMonnies in Paris, becoming a National Academician in 1934. She married William Blanchard Rand in 1911 and settled in Salisbury, Connecticut. After the stock market crash of 1929, Bay's portraits of prominent society figures provided most of her family's income.
Scope and Content Note
The Emmet family papers span the years 1792 to 1989 (bulk 1851-1989) and measure 9.5 linear feet. They consist of biographical material, diaries, correspondence, notes, writings, business records, a scrapbook, art work, subject files, printed material, photographs, audio-visual material, and artifacts which present a good overview of the careers of portraitists, sisters Rosina Emmet Sherwood, Lydia Field Emmet, and Jane Erin Emmet De Glehn, and their cousin Ellen Gertrude "Bay" Emmet.
The Biographical Material Series contains general family trees and family histories. It also contains individual biographical accounts, award certificates, and personal documentation for Julia Colt Pierson Emmet, Rosina Emmet Sherwood, Lydia Field Emmet, Jane Erin Emmet, and Wilfrid De Glehn.
There are two volumes of Diaries: the "Sedgemere Diary" containing drawings and entries primarily by Rosina Emmet Sherwood, and a smaller diary which mentions Rosina's son, future playwright Robert Sherwood.
The largest series in the collection is Correspondence which illustrates the interaction between members of this large and influential family and their colleagues and friends, offering a wide-ranging view of life in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. The series consists of letters between family members, primarily Julia Colt Pierson Emmet and her daughters, as well as cousins Henry James, Ellen "Bay" Emmet Rand, and Rosamond Sherwood, and friend Cecilia Beaux. Topics include the Emmets' experiences while studying art in Paris, Rosina's presentation at Queen Victoria's court, Lydia's work at the Columbia Exposition, Jane's friendship with John Singer Sargent, portrait painting activities, the troubles of their friend Susy Metcalfe's marriage to Pablo Casals, and the activities of Rosina's son, playwright Robert Emmet Sherwood and friends Alfred Lund and Lynn Fontanne.
Notes include address books, illustrated notebooks, lecture notes, and miscellaneous lists.
Included in the Writings Series are manuscripts describing family activities, and poems.
The Business Records Series contains a document concerning ownership of property, a contract for the reproduction of Lydia's work, and account books.
Theree scrapbooks contain a combination of drawings, reproductions of art work, and photographs.
The Art Work Series contains drawings and sketchbooks by Julia Colt Pierson Emmet, Rosina Emmet Sherwood, Lydia Field Emmet, Jane Erin Emmet, Ellen Emmet Rand, and other Emmet relatives, illustrating the early development of their talent.
Subject Files include printed material and photographs concerning Prang's Christmas card competition, and the Danforth exhibition. A file on the exhibitions, "The Emmets: A Family of Women Painters" contains letters, writings, registrarial records, photographs, clippings, and audio cassettes.
Printed Material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, reproductions of art work by Emmet family members, and a book Out of Town, written and illustrated by Rosina Emmet Sherwood.
The Photographs Series contains photographs of family members, including Robert Emmet Sherwood as a young man, friends Richard Harding Davis, Frederick MacMonnies, Augustus Saint-Gaudens. There are also photographs of art work by the Emmets.
Contained in the Audio-Visual Material Series is a videotape The Emmets: Portrait of a Family by Nancy B. Doyle, which gives an excellent overview of the lives and careers of this artistic family.
The Artifacts series consists of a rear-view optical device and locks of hair from an early nineteenth century generation of the Emmet family.
Arrangement
The Emmet family papers are arranged into thirteen series, based on type of document. Individual files for each family member have been maintained in several series to facilitate access.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1881-1981, undated (box 1, OV 13, 7 folders)
Series 2: Diaries, 1855-1933 (box 1, 2 folders)
Series 3: Correspondence, 1792-1985, undated (boxes 1-7, 5.6 linear ft.)
Series 4: Notes, 1878-1978, undated (box 7, 9 folders)
Series 5: Writings, 1877-1936, undated (box 7, 11 folders)
Series 6: Business Records, 1880-1945, undated (boxes 7-8, 7 folders)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1870-1895, undated (sols 11-12, 0.6 linear ft.)
Series 8: Artwork, 1854-1895, undated (boxes 8 and sol 11, 0.6 linear ft.)
Series 9: Subject Files, 1947-1982, undated (box 8, 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 10: Printed Material, 1872-1989 (boxes 8 and 11, 0.4 linear ft.)
Series 11: Photographs, 1875-1944 (boxes 9, 10, sol 11, 1.2 linear ft.)
Series 12: Videotape: The Emmets: Portrait of a Family, 1988 (box 10, 1 folder)
Series 13: Artifacts, undated (box 10, 2 folders)
Appendix: List of Notable Correspondents from Series 3: Correspondence, 1792-1985, undated
This appendix is a detailed, though not all-inclusive, chronological listing of notable correspondence found in the chronologically arranged Series 3: Correspondence, 1792-1985, and undated. Subjects mentioned in one letter may also be discussed in the unlisted letters which surround it. The appendix begins with a listing of frequently mentioned Emmet family members and friends in order to clarify their identities.
Arsie: Archibald Sherwood, Posie's grandson
Aunty: Lydia Hubley Emmet
Bay: Ellen Emmet Rand
Bobby: Robert Emmet Sherwood, Posie's son
Dev: Devereux Emmet, Posie's brother
Dooly: Julia Townsend, Posie's granddaughter
E.B.S.: Elsie Burr Sherwood
Elly: Ellen James Temple, Bay's mother
Bob Emmet: Robert Temple Emmet, Posie's twin brother
W.J. Emmet: William Jenkins Emmet, Posie's husband
Gaggy: Rosina Emmet Sherwood (her nickname as a grandmother; her other nickname "Posie" has been used throughout the finding aid)
Ginny: Virginia Clementine Sherwood, Posie's granddaughter
Jane: Jane Erin Emmet De Glehn
Jank: Robert Emmet Sherwood
Julia: Julia Colt Pierson Emmet (letters from her children will often contain the salutation "Mammy", but her Christian name has been used throughout the finding aid)
Kob: Marie O. Kobbe, artist friend of Lydia
Leslie: Edith Leslie Emmet, Bay's sister
Lybba: Elizabeth Emmet Morgan
Lydia: Lydia Field Emmet
Mammy: Julia Colt Pierson Emmet
Mox: Marie O. Kobbe (?), artist friend of Lydia
Nelly: Helena Phelps, wife of Robert Temple Emmet, Posie's sister-in-law
Nite: Anita Helena Emmet, Posie's niece
Posie: Rosina Emmet Sherwood (letters exchanged with her children may refer to her as "Mother", but her nickname "Posie" has been used throughout the finding aid)
R.E.S.: Rosina Emmet Sherwood
Roger: Roger Quilter, composer of operas
Ros: Rosamond Sherwood
Susie: Susie Metcalfe Casals, wife of Pablo Casals
Wilfrid: Wilfred Gabriel De Glehn (originally Von Glehn)
Winty: Winthrop Emmet
Undated To: Rosina - From: [illegible name] - Subject: saw Eastman Johnson
Undated To: Lydia - From: Agnes
Undated To: Lydia - From: Annie
Undated To: Mrs. Von Glehn - From: B.
Undated To: Lydia - From: Farnie
Undated To: Lydia - From: Jack
Undated To: ? - From: Lydia
Undated To: Lydia - From: Maggie
Undated To: Lydia - From: Maria
Undated To: Lydia - From: Adele Allen
Undated To: Jane - From: Kitsy B.
Undated To: Julia - From: Andrew Carnegie - Subject: his mother is feeble
Undated To: Lydia - From: _____ Cutter
Undated To: Lydia- From: Jane Emmet De Glehn - Subjects: Bay; Harry and Ellen; (drawing of polo player); Harry and Dorothea James (Jul 11 and 18 letters)
Undated To: W. J. Emmet - From: W. Duncan
Undated To: Jane - From: Alida Emmet - Subject: thanks for portraits
Undated To: Lydia - From: Bay Emmet - Subjects: gossip about Mary; Uncle Dick
Undated To: Nellie - From: Devereaux Emmet - Subject: saw the President about Robert's appointment
Undated To: Julia - From: Ella Emmet - Subject: wants to see color in Elizabeth's cheeks
Undated To: Posie, Lydia, and Jane - From: Julia Colt Emmet -Subjects: Jane met Dana Gibsons on Long Island train (in "Tuesday" letter to Lydia); Jane went to ____ James' to meet Baring and McKim (in "Friday" letter to Lydia); Henry James told Elly that he found Leslie cultivated; Bay at Holland House (in Sep 8 letter to Lydia)
Undated - To: Leslie - From: young Harry
Undated - To: Julia, Jane, and Posie - From: Lydia Field Emmet
Undated - To: Lydia - From: [illegible] - Subject: Marcus Reynolds
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Alice - Subject: Salot's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Bud - Subject: Maizy's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Madeleine - Subject: Philip
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Paul - Subject: Alice's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Harriet Aldrich - Subject: how to hang portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: E. Baker - Subjects: lend portrait of 2 girls; Lybba's rings
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Mrs. Daniel Moore Bates - Subject: likes portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: E. Borie - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Geraldine Walker Browne - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: George Cabot - Subject: payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Cornelia Channing - Subject: thanks for Philby picture
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Kitty Cooper - Subject: payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Margaret Corlies - Subject: loves portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: P. Coudert - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Emily De Rham - Subject: wants daughter's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Lucy Eliot - Subject: thanks for viewing of Lydia's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Helen J. Ga____ - Subject: copy of Philby portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Elizabeth Haskell - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Helen Hazard - Subject: can't part with portrait of boys
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Mary C. Hunnewell - Subject: portrait of Kitty
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Mrs. Joseph Holand Hunt (Mazie Eliz. Hunt) - Subject: compliment from Lord Craig
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Dorothy Hutton - Subject: loves portrait of Joan
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Harry C. J____ - Subject: loves Jean's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: John? L____ - Subject: thanks for portraits
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Beatrice Levy - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Mabel Lockwood - Subject: trying to get Cliefs' portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Elfrieda Martin - Subject: portrait of Nancy needs change
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Lydia Maxwell - Subject: lend portrait in January
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Emily Morris - Subjects: Katharine Twichell; Peggy's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Helen Mullaney - Subject: portrait of Princess
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Richard Newton - Subject: portrait of Princess
Undated - To: Lydia - From: J.P.? - Subject: children's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Helen Paton - Subject: Pam's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Dorothy T. Potter - Subject: loves portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Elizabeth Power - Subject: portrait of boys and of Miss Scott
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Dorothy Prentice - Subject: took portrait for repair
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Maud Howland Pyne - Subject: payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Jessie H. R____ - Subject: Philby portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: B. Averell Roger____ - Subject: loves child's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Peggy Rudkin - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Mary Runnells - Subject: thanks for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: ____ Schley - Subject: payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Elsie Nicholl Sloan - Subject: loves portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Sophie ______ - Subject: portrait of Olivia Stokes
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Dorothy Thomas - Subject: James will be at studio; payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Adelaide Thomson - Subject: wants to change portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Burton Twichell - Subject: portrait of Peggy
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Sam M. Vauclain - Subject: payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Mary Whitehouse - Subject: Sylvia's portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: D. Witt - Subject: wants portrait of Anne
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Helen Woods - Subject: payment for portrait
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Nelly Emmet - Subject: Bob Emmet upset about staircase
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Nite (Anita) Emmet - Subjects: Barrie plays; Zogbaum poem
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Lucie Fuller
Undated - To: Jane - From: John Ireland
Undated - To: Bay and Elly- From: Henry James (3 transcripts) - Subject: description of travels
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Marie O. Kobbe
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Jane Lake
Undated - To: Lydia - From: H. Magee
Undated(business card) - From: Payson McL. Merrill Company
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Lucien Monod (postcard in French)
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Hobart Nichols - Subject: did not receive work in time for jury
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Jessie H. R. - Subject: thanks to the Sargents (Mar 22 letter)
Undated - To: Jane - From: John Singer Sargent - Subject: thanks for Faberge dish
Undated - To: Posie - From: Arthur Sherwood, Jr. - Subject: school activities
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Cynthia Sherwood - Subject: thanks for necklace
Undated - To: Posie - From: Phil Sherwood - Subject: family matters
Undated - To: Julia, Lydia, and Jane - From: Posie (Rosina Emmet) Sherwood - Subject: Lybba and Eddie to stay with the Jays in Vermont; Alty Morgan bought a farm (Oct. 18 letter)
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Ros(amond) Sherwood - Subject: thanks for visit
Undated - To: Lydia - From: Lillian and Anthony Thieme, and Louise D. Van And____
Undated - To: Posie - From: Stanford White - Subject: thanks for picture 1792 - To: Mrs. McCoubry- From: Thomas Addis Emmet (fragment)
Jul 9, 1851 - To: Julia - From: William Travers (in Baltimore) - Subject: description of travels
Aug 8, 1857 - To: Julia (45 Williams St., N.Y.) - From: W. J. Emmet - Subject: journey from Boston to Portland
Dec 28, 1858 - To: Julia (91 Beaver St., N.Y.) - From: C.W.C. (Catherine Wadsworth Colt ?) - Subjects: Mr. Hornblower; Gilbert did not come; the Misses Johnson
Jan 8, 1861 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet (in Philadelphia) - Subjects: Bob and Herman; visit to the picture gallery
Jan 9 and 10, 1861 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet (in Washington, D.C.) - Subject: saw Jefferson Davis in Congress
Jan 12, 1861 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet - Subject: Civil War
Nov 5, 1862 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet (in Worthington) - Subject: sport shooting; Cunard
Nov 16, 1863 - To: Cousin July - From: Julia - Subject: the Confederacy
Oct 28, 1864 - To: Julia - From W. J. Emmet (in Toledo) - Subject: duck shooting
Oct 3, 1865 - To: Dear Sir - From: R. or E. Emmet (in New Rochelle) - Subject: Mr. Graves at point of death
Nov 28, 1866 - To: Amy Toler - From: Posie (in New York) - Subject: won't forget the Philippines
Aug 4, 1867 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet - Subject: Nelly James married John March; Wilkie James
Aug 1870 ? - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet - Subject: [Oliver Wendell] Holmes; William and Henry James
Jul 26, 1871 - To: Aunty - From: Posie - Subject: Oliver Wendell Holmes
Aug 6, 1871 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Bache Emmet; "Mt. Hope"; games
Mar 1872 - To: Judge Emmet?- From: Dufferin (at Exhibition Palace, Dublin)
Oct 6?, 1872 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet (in London) - Subjects: Cambridge races; Bache Cunard
Oct 11, 1872 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet - Subjects: Fanny Allen; Harold and William Power
Oct 26, 1872 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet - Subject: Brighton; Cowes
Nov 10, 1872 - To: Julia - From: W. J. Emmet - Subject: Cambridge; rugby; Aunt Jane's room at Hallaton Hall
Nov 19, 1872 - To: Father - From: W. J. Emmet (in London) - Subject: in Dublin 2 days; exhibition; William Power 1873 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Miss Doyle; new rooms in house; Lydia writes opposition letter
May 27, 1873 - To: Aunty - From: Posie - Subjects: Jeanette to West Point; trunk keys; Mrs. Green
[summer 1873] - To: July - From: Julia - Subjects: Bob Emmet to West Point; (drawing of farm)
Jun 8, 1873 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Henriette sailed; West Point cadets; (drawings of cadets and woman in hat)
[circa 1873] - To: July - From: Julia (at West Point) - Subjects: Gen. Orland Bollivar wants Posie
Aug 19, 1873 - To: Posie - From: Bache Cunard - Subjects: sporting activities; (drawings of a hunter and polo player)
Feb 4, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: mother's lame leg; Nilsson; Julia Ward Howe
Feb 5, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Nilsson; Julia Ward Howe; (drawing of Howe's granddaughter)
Feb 9, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Boston) - Subject: Nilsson's performance; Mr. Griswold's party; (drawings of children at play)
Feb 9, 1874 - To: Rich - From: Posie - Subject: Nilsson in Faust
Feb 16, 1874 - To: Julia - From: George Robeson (Navy Department) - Subject: position for her son
Aug 5, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Newport) - Subjects: just left Southampton; Mrs. Archie Pell; Charley Russell
Aug 8, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: saw Julia Ward Howe dancing; Mr. Forbes' yacht
Aug 16, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Narragansett) - Subjects: Frank Abbot; plans for West Point; the 2 Baches; Mr. Pickering, actor; Mrs. Ball Hughes, wife of sculptor
Aug 21, 1874 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Mr. Pickering; Mr. Bennet; sad news about cousin Meta; (drawing of Mrs. Sprague)
Mar 30, 1875 - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Washington, D.C.) - Subjects: toured Washington, D.C.; Mr. Hoyt; Mrs. Julia Meigs
Apr 1875 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: party at Postmaster Gen. Jewell's home; Robeson gave appointment; (drawing of Miss Meigs and of cousin Janey's house)
[April 1875] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Robeson dinner; to visit Mount Vernon; (drawing of a man with flamboyant whiskers)
[April 1875] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: visited Mount Vernon; Mr. Bouliniere; climbed Capitol dome
Jun 4, 1875 - To: Julie - From: Posie - Subject: West Point
Aug 1875 - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Maine) - Subjects: Mr. Hoyt; Wynnie is ill
Apr 9, 1876 - To: W. J. Emmet - From: Posie (in Washington, D.C.) - Subjects: visited House of Representatives; the Robesons; the Frelinghuysens; Sothern, the actor
[April 1876] - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: met Miss Washington, a relative of George Washington
Apr 14, 1876 - To: W. J. Emmet - From: Posie - Subjects: will visit Senate, Corcoran Gallery, and the Smithsonian
Apr 22, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: will visit Arlington; Lucy's engagement off
Apr 24, 1876 - To: W. J. Emmet - From: Posie - Subjects: Mr. Hoyt wants to go to the impeachment to hear the Marshs' testimony
[Apr 1876] - To: Little Sister - From: Posie (in Washington, D.C.) - Subject: Easter egg roll at the Capitol
Jun 28, [1876] - To: Julia - From: Posie (at West Point) - Subject: journey to West Point
Jun 30, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subject: West Point activities; (drawings of Fourth of July celebrants)
Aug 23, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Lydia (at West Point) - Subject: Mr. Barber to marry Miss Townsend
Aug 27, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: Miss Townsend's invitation to Albany; group photo taken by Gotthelf Pach
Sep 29, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie (on ship to Hallaton and Ireland) - Subjects: Mr. Barrington; (drawings of activities on ship)
Oct 8, 1876 - To: family - From: Posie (Hallaton Hall, England) - Subject: Aunt Jane getting deaf
Oct 22, 1876 - To: Aunty - From: Posie (in London) - Subjects: London sightseeing; Barry Sullivan in Richard III; saw Prince and Princess of Wales and Louis of Hesse at Haymarket Theatre
Oct 25, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie (in Paris) - Subject: Nilsson in audience for Mme. Judie in La Belle Helene
Oct 29, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: sightseeing; Mr. May's studio; Sarah Bernhardt in Rome Vaincu; the Bells and Pierpont Morgans in church; Miss Wise; Hallaton skeleton
Nov 5, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie (Hallaton Hall) - Subjects: Bache Cunard; fox hunt
Nov 25, 1876 - To: Julia - From: Posie - Subjects: steeple chase; A .D.C. theatre; Sir John Kaye, actor, and Cecil Kaye; (drawing of girl)
Nov 27, 1876 - To: Chicky - From: Posie - Subjects: steeple chase; Mrs. Franklyn to U.S.; (drawing of a carriage)
Nov 29, 1876 - To: Bobby Emmet - From: Posie - Subject: (drawings of Mamy on Caramel the horse and of Billson the groom)